{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "In Ancient times, Assam is also known by the name of",
        "options": [
          "A. Koliabor",
          "B. Guwahati",
          "C. Pragjyotishpur",
          "D. Charaideo"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Pragjyotishpur"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which hilltop, the Kamakhya Temple is located",
        "options": [
          "A. Nilachal Hill",
          "B. Chitrachal Hill",
          "C. Sandhyachal Hill",
          "D. Jogini Hill"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Nilachal Hill"
      },
      {
        "question": "In which year, the capital of Assam shifted from Shillong to Dispur",
        "options": [
          "A. 1950",
          "B. 1955",
          "C. 1971",
          "D. 1973"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 1973"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Asam Sahitya Sabha was first founded in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1902",
          "B. 1912",
          "C. 1917",
          "D. 1921"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 1917"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first conference of Asam Sahitya Sabha was held at",
        "options": [
          "A. Kamrup",
          "B. Sivasagar",
          "C. Barpeta",
          "D. Dhuburi"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Sivasagar"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who was the first President of Asam Sahitya Sabha",
        "options": [
          "A. Lakshminath Bezbaroa",
          "B. Padmanath Gohain Baruah",
          "C. Hemchandra Goswami",
          "D. Rajanikanta Bordoloi"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Padmanath Gohain Baruah"
      },
      {
        "question": "Total number of National Parks in Assam",
        "options": [
          "A. 3",
          "B. 4",
          "C. 6",
          "D. 7"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 7"
      },
      {
        "question": "Total number of bridges over the river Brahmaputra",
        "options": [
          "A. 4",
          "B. 5",
          "C. 6",
          "D. 7"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 6"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Naranarayan Setu connects the Pancharatna Town with which city",
        "options": [
          "A. Kalibor",
          "B. Tezpur",
          "C. Bongaigaon",
          "D. Jogighopa"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Jogighopa"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who was the first Chief Minister of Assam",
        "options": [
          "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
          "B. Tarun Ram Phukan",
          "C. Gopinath Bordoloi",
          "D. None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Gopinath Bordoloi"
      },
      {
        "question": "Srimanta Sankardev was born in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1352",
          "B. 1432",
          "C. 1449",
          "D. 1465"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 1449"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first Assamese film Joymoti was released in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1922",
          "B. 1935",
          "C. 1938",
          "D. 1942"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 1935"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Abhiruchi Sports Day is celebrated on",
        "options": [
          "A. January 13th",
          "B. August 12th",
          "C. August 30th",
          "D. September 3rd"
        ],
        "answer": "D. September 3rd"
      },
      {
        "question": "Bhogeswar Baruah wins a medal in the ________ Asian Games",
        "options": [
          "A. 1962",
          "B. 1966",
          "C. 1978",
          "D. 1972"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 1966"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who was the last king of Ahom kingdom in Assam",
        "options": [
          "A. Gobar Roja",
          "B. Sutanphaa",
          "C. Purandar Singha",
          "D. Jogeswar Singha"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Purandar Singha"
      }
    ]
  }
  